


















    
        
    

    
        
    







    






<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"  xml:lang="en"  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://pitchhh.github.io/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

        

        <description>Recent content</description>

        
            <language>en</language>
        

        
            <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 10:10:20 +08</lastBuildDate>
        

        <link>https://pitchhh.github.io/blog/</link>

        

        <title>Blogs · </title>

        

        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>This weekend, I brewed my second cup of coffee with an Aeropress &amp; a Chestnut C2 hand grinder! After a relaxing yoga class, I passed by The Alchemist cafe and spontaneously picked up some Filter Espresso beans to experiment with. These beans, hailing from Guji in Ethiopia, promised a vibrant, citrusy, slightly acidic, and sweet experience, with tasting notes of bergamot, apricot, and blueberry.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<span class="paige-image">
<img  alt="Shakiso Tero"   class="object-fit-cover"  crossorigin="anonymous"  fetchpriority="high"    referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="https://pitchhh.github.io/Coffee_ShakisoTero.jpg"   style="height: 20rem; width: 20rem"   >
</span>
</div>
<br />
<p>The first time I got introduced to my new brewing toys was in Casablanca, during my Morocco trip, as I received them as a gift. It was a very special first brew, from the anticipation of grinding and brewing the medium dark roast beans I roasted myself at a coffee farm in Chiang Mai, Thailand, back in January 2024. The Chestnut C2 hand grinder is super fun to use. It&rsquo;s incredibly satisfying to feel the beans releasing their aroma as you grind them - an aromatic journey that took only 30 seconds.</p>
<p>The AeroPress itself is also a fascinating product. Its ease of use and straightforward cleaning process impressed me, making the brewing ritual both enjoyable and hassle-free. The best part is both products have such compact design that I could see myself taking them with me on my trips in the future.</p>
<p>Noting down the recipe I used this time for future reference &amp; improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Beans:
<ul>
<li>Shakiso Tero (dark roast)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Grind:
<ul>
<li>15g for 250g water (half of my grinder’s capacity)</li>
<li>Coarser grind (20 clicks counterclockwise)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Brew:
<ul>
<li>Upright Aeropress setup</li>
<li>Stir for about 30 seconds</li>
<li>Wait for coffee extraction for about 3 minutes (this might be why my brew had a deeper, more bitter taste - can try 2 minutes next time)</li>
<li>1.5 cups of coffee (top-up pour twice)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Taste:
<ul>
<li>Slightly bitter and just a tad acidic</li>
<li>Very smooth and aromatic</li>
<li>Thin texture and easy to drink</li>
<li>Sweet and chocolatey aftertaste</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:pitchhh.github.io,2024-06-16:2024-06-16T10:10:20+08:00</guid>

                
                    <link>https://pitchhh.github.io/2024/06/16/my-brewing-journey/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 10:10:20 +08</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>My Brewing Journey</title>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                
                
                
                
                
                

                

                

                

                

                
                

                

                
                    
                

                

                

                

                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hello world!</p>
]]></description>
                

                <guid  isPermaLink="false" >tag:pitchhh.github.io,2024-05-25:2024-05-25T17:21:17+08:00</guid>

                
                    <link>https://pitchhh.github.io/2024/05/25/first-post/</link>
                

                
                    <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 17:21:17 +08</pubDate>
                

                
                    <title>First Post</title>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
